Daniel Wamuya

Full Stack Software Engineer

Phone: (254) 0798 164 378 | Email: dwamuya@gmail.com | Website: dwamuya.me Github: github.com/dannywamuya | Address: Nairobi, Kenya

Summary

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 1 year of related experience.

Skills

- Java
- Typescript/Javascript(ES6)
- Spring Boot
- Node.js
- Angular

Work Experience

Afrex Gold Limited

Full Stack Developer - Thika, Kenya

Feb 2021 to August 2021

- Conceived and built an optimized website with Angular and Nodejs including node-mailer integration and cross-browser compatibility to support marketing.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.

MyMoviesAfrica

Android Developer Intern - Nairobi, Kenya

Dec 2020 to Jan 2021

- Led highly productive scrum team of developers reviewing and testing submitted code to ensure a streamlined and bug safe development process.
- Applied integration and unit testing to locate bugs and errors in previously built and newly integrated software solutions for speedy issue resolution.
- Developed and implemented new features to aid with user experience.

Education

Moringa School

Full Stack Software Development

August 2020 to Jan 2021

- Specialised in Android development with Java and Android Studio with NoSQL databases for scalable data storage on Firebase.
- Learned web development with SparkJava for RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL for scalable databases and Angular for frontend development.